elabs10.com 2011-05-19

# Privacy Policy

The following statement (this “Statement”) discloses the policies of Lyris, Inc. (which is sometimes referred to in this Privacy Policy as "Lyris," the "Company," "we," or "us") with respect to information that we collect from visitors to our corporate Web site ([www.lyris.com](http://www.lyris.com/)).  This Statement also contains our end user opt-out mechanism.  Unless otherwise provided in this Statement, this Statement does not apply to our offline data practices.  This Statement is effective as of the date set forth above. 

This Statement applies to the operation of any Web site that directly links to this Statement when you click on “privacy statement” in the Web site footer.

The Company has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Statement and our privacy practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions.  If you have questions or complaints regarding this Statement or our practices, please contact us as provided below.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

The TRUSTe program does not cover any software that may be downloaded from our Web site.

## **Definitions**

"Personal Information" or "Information" means information that (1) is about, or pertains to a specific individual; and (2) can be linked to that individual.

"Sensitive Personal Information" means financial data, such as credit card number or social security number.

## **Privacy Principles**

### **Notice**

You can visit and navigate through our main, corporate Web Site ([www.lyris.com](http://www.lyris.com/)) to gather information about our company and Services without telling us who you are and without otherwise revealing any type of Personal Information.

Our website does offer several opportunities for visitors to register for free information, seminars, or demonstration copies of our software, and for assistance in evaluating our software and services.  These registration forms are often linked to Lyris mailing lists, and require users to provide Personal Information (such as name and e-mail address), which we use to send users information about our company and our products and services.  We also use this information to contact site visitors by e-mail for marketing purposes if they have granted us permission (on the mailing list form or other forms on our website) to send it to them, and for administrative purposes such as providing time and location of seminars.  Users may also be contacted by phone or postal mail for marketing purposes.

We use information that is not Personal Information (e.g., IP address) to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website.  IP addresses are also used to gather broad, personally non-identifiable demographic information, such the countries in our Web site visitors live.

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes.  We use cookies on this site.  We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.  We also have third party cookies and other tracking technologies on our site, of which data is only collected in the aggregate.

Our website contains testimonials that contain information such as Customer names and titles.  Lyris obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a colleague our site, we request to receive from you Personal Information about your friend and you, such as name, company name, email address, and phone number.  We only use this information to contact the referred colleague (once) to see if they wish to receive information from us and to track the success of our referral program.  This Personal Information is not otherwise used if the referred colleague does not wish to have contact from us.  If the referred person agrees to be contacted by Lyris, then their Personal Information is retained and used by us in the same way as we retain and use Personal Information as described above. 

Our Web site includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company _(_ e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc _)._   Personal Information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget.  Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly.  Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it, which you can access by scrolling over the Widget.

We allow users to access Facebook Connect to interact with friends and to share on Facebook through Wall and friends' News Feeds.  If you are already logged into our Web site and Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to merge your profiles.  If you are already logged into our Web site but not logged into Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to enter your Facebook credentials or to “Sign up for Facebook.”  By proceeding, you are allowing our Web site to access your information and you are also agreeing to the Facebook Terms of Use in your use of our Web site.

Conversely, if you are not currently registered as a Lyris user and you click on “Sign in Using Facebook,” you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join our Web site.  Once you register on our Web site and Connect with Facebook, you will be able to automatically post recent activity back to Facebook.  You have the option to disable Facebook Connect at any time by logging into “My Profile” and clicking on “My Facebook Profile.”  Further, you can edit privacy settings for the reviews that appear on Facebook or disconnect this service by visiting the Facebook Application Settings page.

Our website contains links to other sites.  Lyris is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites and recommends that you check the privacy policies of other sites to be aware of how your information is being used.

### **Choice**

Any Personal Information collected by Lyris is used for the sole purpose of communicating with prospects, customers, and contacts that have requested to receive information from us regarding specific marketing events, materials, or other information specifically advertised by Lyris in promotional material.  You have the ability to “opt-out” or unsubscribe from any Lyris’ communications via email, phone, mail, or fax (provided below) at anytime.  Lyris also provides opt-out information in all marketing communications via an “unsubscribe” link in communication emails which directly unsubscribes you from any further communication from Lyris.

### **Access**

We allow our Web site visitors to access their Personal Information and allow them to correct, amend or delete inaccurate information, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the privacy of the individual in the case in question or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated.  Customers may request that we update, amend, or delete their Personal Information by following the Profile Update link in every Lyris e-mail communication.  Alternatively, you can contact us as described below if you would like your Personal Information deleted.  We will respond to your request within 30 business days.

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with information or services.  If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us as described below.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### **Onward Transfers**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Statement.  The Personal Information we collect is not shared, rented, or sold to any third-parties.  We may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service.  These companies are authorized to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.  We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; 
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; 
  * if we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets,  you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information; and 
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### **Customer Data**

Lyris provides online marketing services and products to its customers.  These services include customer database management and analysis, e-mail delivery, e-mail tracking and website tracking.  For all customers, Lyris has written agreements regarding the confidentiality of each customer’s data  
Lyris is not responsible for its customers' own privacy policies and makes no representations about their accuracy.  If you have questions about our customers' practices, we recommend you check their privacy policies and/or contact them directly.

### **Data Security**

Lyris takes reasonable steps to protect Personal Information in its possession from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.  We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction.  However, we cannot guarantee the security of information on, or transmitted via, the Internet.

### **Data Integrity**

Lyris processes Personal Information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized by the owning individual.  To the extent necessary for those purposes, we take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is accurate, complete, current and reliable for its intended use.

### **Safe** **Harbor** ****

The Company respects and protects the individual privacy and confidence of our customers, stakeholders, employees, business partners and others who may use our services. Protecting consumer privacy is important to the Company. The Company adheres to the Safe Harbor Agreement concerning the transfer of personal data from the European Union (“EU”) to the United States of America ([European Union Safe Harbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "European Union Safe Harbor")).  Accordingly, we follow the Seven (7) Safe Harbor Principles published by the U.S. Department of Commerce (the “Principles”) with respect to all such data.  Our privacy practices are self-certified as part of the [U.S. Commerce Department's Safe Harbor Program](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "U.S. Commerce Department's Safe Harbor Program").  Information regarding the E.U. Safe Harbor Framework can be found at:  <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

If there is any conflict between the policies in this Statement and the Principles, the Principles shall govern. This Statement outlines our general policy and practices for implementing the Principles, including the types of information we gather, how we use it and the notice and choice affected individuals have regarding our use of and their ability to correct that information.

### **Enforcement**

Company utilizes a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this Statement and periodically verifies that the Statement is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible.  We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns using the contact information provided below, and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and/or disputes regarding our use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with this Statement.  We also have a third party dispute resolution provider, TRUSTe.  You can contact TRUSTe as described above.

### **Children**

This Web site is not intended to nor does it seek to receive any information from children under the age of 13.

## **Contact Information**

Questions or comments regarding this Statement can be submitted to us by mail or e-mail as follows:

Lyris Inc  
6401 Hollis Street   
Suite 125   
Emeryville, CA 94608   
510.844.1505 (phone)  
510.355.3700 (fax)

## **Amendments**

This Statement may be amended from time to reflect changes to our information practices.  If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective.  We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## **Information Subject to Other Policies**

The Company is committed to following the Principles for all Personal Information within the scope of the Safe Harbor Agreement. However, certain information is subject to policies of the Company that may differ in some respects from the general policies set forth in this Privacy Policy.

---
